Find your Passion
So, there was a wonderful article by Steven Kotler, published in Forbes about How to find your passion.
It's a question we ask ourselves every single day.
We've all been told that a life of passion is a life that means something.
But how do we identify our passions?
It's not always easy.
So one of the things that Steven Kotler breaks down is that he says that
passion essentially exists in the intersection between multiple things that you're curious about.
So he says, "The first thing you should do if you wanna identify you passion is to make a list
of all the things that you're curious about."
All the things that you wonder about.
Be specific as you can.
And then create a kind of a Venn diagram,
and try to figure out where the things that you're curious about, three or more, intersect.
And that's the sweet spot.
That's where there is energy, that's where there is dopamine and neurobiology.
Multiple streams of curiosity intersect at a space called passion, right?
And then once you've identified your passion,
then you can figure out how to turn that passion into a purpose.
Turn that passion into a purpose.
Make a list of fifteen things in the world,
fifteen challenges you'd like to see solved.
And figure out which one of those challenges can be served by your passion.
So then you see it.
Curiosity leads to passion.
Multiple streams of curiosity leads to passion.
Identifying problems in the world that can be served by your passion leads to purpose.
And then, my friends, you've impregnated your life with a sense of significance, with as sense of meaning.
And then you can go forth, my brothers.
You can go forth.
I thought it was a great article.
Take note, Steven Kotler's work, Flow Genome Project,
How to Find your Passion and Your Flow.